<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
     >
  <channel>
    <title>Oblivion</title>
    <link>http://mrsesaman.com/blog</link>
    <description>Shall not be forgotten</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 21:34:35 GMT</pubDate>
    <generator>Blogofile</generator>
    <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
    <item>
      <title>180 lbs</title>
      <link>http://mrsesaman.com/blog/2014/11/04/180-lbs</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 22:00:00 EST</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[miscellaneous]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">m-GrV9B-RkxUox1xarSrGKZJgoY=</guid>
      <description>180 lbs</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Weight losing for about 6 weeks now, and I've lost about 15 lbs.</p>
<p>Gladly, I achieved 15 lbs today.</p>
<p>Below is a chart plotted with daily recorded data of my bodyweight. According current trend, I still need a little bit more than two months to complete the goal of 160 lbs.
If everything goes well, I may write something about my experience of fitness and weight losing later.</p>
<iframe width="657" height="371" seamless frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1g9xVAk_aST3kzorVhbB-hdrjY7QKu8kYlilfRl62h-c/pubchart?oid=198236923&amp;format=interactive"></iframe>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trip to Yellowstone National Park</title>
      <link>http://mrsesaman.com/blog/2014/09/24/trip-to-yellowstone-national-park</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 13:40:00 EDT</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[traveling]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">CmhXEIIBCpr3_zKwenxkIXZSKJY=</guid>
      <description>Trip to Yellowstone National Park</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>先挖个坑，慢慢补全
7月份去了 Yellowstone，算是来美国以后真正意义上第一次去国家公园吧。(虽然春假去了 Great Smoky Mountain，但是那一趟实在太水了，都没有 Hiking..以后有机会要重新再去一次)。
自己很坑的用胶片机照了所有的照片，但是现在也没有选上 B&amp;W Photography 的课，于是拍的两卷也不知道什么时候才能洗出来了。目测只有下次回国的时候拿回去洗了。</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>读书笔记－傅雷家书（1）</title>
      <link>http://mrsesaman.com/blog/2014/09/06/du-shu-bi-ji--fu-lei-jia-shu-(1)</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 10:36:18 EDT</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">kyVAQbHDD5VZMuQenVqRtdExsQ0=</guid>
      <description>读书笔记－傅雷家书（1）</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>近来不打 DotA 了，于是晚上多了些时间。手边也只有这么一本书，就拿来读读。</p>
<p>回想起来自己高中以来没有好好地看书了，平时看的也都是些理工科类的书，教材一类的，人文相关的书几乎没有接触过。时间大多被游戏与网络瓜分，现在想想这些实在不好。所谓思而不学则殆，这么6、7年的空缺但愿还能补得回来。</p>
<p>这三天看了几十页，里面书信的时间大概是五十年代中期，是当时傅雷与其长子傅聪的日常交流，大约1-2周便有一封信。傅聪到俄罗斯、波兰学习音乐，年龄也与我们这些留学生相仿，甚至还要年轻一些。傅雷夫妇在书信中给了傅聪许多建议，许多我看来现在也还是适用的。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>接十七日信，很高兴你又过了一关。人生的苦难，theme 不过是这几个，其余只是 variations 而已。爱情的苦汁早尝，壮年中年可以比较冷静。古语说得好，塞翁失马，未始非福。你比一般青年经历人事都更早，所以成熟也早。这一回痛苦的经验，大概又使你灵智的长成进了一步。... <em>1954.04.21</em></p>
<p>其次，我不得不再提醒你一句：尽量控制自己的感情，把它转移到艺术中去。你周围美好的天使太多了，我怕你又要把持不住。你别忘了，你自誓要做几年清教徒的，在男女之爱方面要过几年禁欲生活的！这一点千万要提醒自己！时时刻刻防自己！一切都要醒悟得早，收蓬收得早；不要让自己的热情升高之后再去压制，那时痛苦更多，而且收效也少。亲爱的孩子，无论如何你要再这方面听从我的忠告！爸爸妈妈最不放心的不过是这些。... <em>1954.08.11</em></p>
<p>你素来有两个习惯：一是到别人家里，进了屋子，脱了大衣却留着丝围巾；二是常常把手插在上衣口袋里，或是裤带里。这两件都不合西洋的礼貌。围巾必须和大衣一同脱在衣帽间，不穿大衣时也要除去围巾。手插在上衣袋里比插在裤袋里更无礼，切忌切忌！... ＊1954.08.16*</p>
</blockquote>
<p>有很多内容值得摘抄，但就摘这些出来。看到傅雷的教育总能让我回想起父母对我的教育。有些相似之处，但是总感觉父母在很多方面并不能做到指点迷津，毕竟我要走的路他们没有走过，只能依赖他们自己的经验来说说，而这些经验往往都太狭隘了。当然这也无法改变，毕竟他们的工作环境也就是这样。他们能从农民家庭里出来走到这一步已经不易，我完全理解。只是希望将来我能比他们做得好一些。</p>
<p>先写这些。</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>注音输入法</title>
      <link>http://mrsesaman.com/blog/2014/07/21/zhu-yin-shu-ru-fa</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 18:04:00 EDT</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[miscellaneous]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">-e4Xs8G36nk1m1veMY3czBse1ZE=</guid>
      <description>注音输入法</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>这是一篇用注音输入法写出的文章！</p>
<p>发现了注音输入法的规律后学习起来就容易多了！</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S14 Summary</title>
      <link>http://mrsesaman.com/blog/2014/05/15/s14-summary</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 05:01:18 EDT</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[miscellaneous]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">W1NQLrMBJJlZycOMpZ8vidEl-YM=</guid>
      <description>S14 Summary</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>All grades are given today. Sadly I got 2 Bs on 06-640 and 39-802.</p>
<p>Basically, I recognize this semester as my most hard working semester in recent few years. However, really shouldn't take 06-640. Totally lost in the content of the course.</p>
<ul>
<li>15-213 is a good course, did learn a lot from it. </li>
<li>39-802 is only based on the report, which is quite unfair.</li>
<li>06-607 introduced me into the field of surfaces and colloids. This is a quite interesting field. I'm considering pursuing Ph.D. in this field. Prof. Prieve gave lectures on a very slow speed. Tests are quite hard, but it's easy to get an A.</li>
<li>06-640 is named as "Molecular Simulation". However, Prof. Kitchin talked very little about the quantem background. Should drop this course.</li>
<li>09-611 is taught by Prof. Gary Patterson, a very nice old man. This thermal dynamic course is more related to polymer thermal dynamics.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some tips on Cachelab</title>
      <link>http://mrsesaman.com/blog/2014/03/01/some-tips-on-cachelab</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 05:01:18 EST</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7sL2_e99wSdCfCtv2Ub9p6CdW5M=</guid>
      <description>Some tips on Cachelab</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ok.. This lab is actually not that difficult. I just made some supid error in the c code which wasted me like 4 hours to find it out.</p>
<p>There are two parts in this lab. Part A asks you to finish a cache simulator, and part B requires you to write a program to transpose matrix with limited cache miss.</p>
<p>For part A, it should be quite easy since only hit count, miss count and eviction count are required. So just malloc some memory and then process each trace and update cache status after each trace. The results are there then.</p>
<p>For part B, it is a little tricky for the case 64 * 64 matrix. What I did is that use a 4 * 8 subset in matrix B as a buffer so it could always be hit when reading or writing these memories.</p>
<p>Assume blow is a submatrix S with size of 8 * 8. And we also vertically seperate the 4 * 8 buffer into to parts, B1 and B2.</p>
<p>|---+---| <br>
| 1 | 2 | <br>
|---+---| <br>
| 3 | 4 | <br>
|---+---| <br></p>
<p>So if we want to transpose S<sub>An</sub> into S<sub>Bm</sub>, the S<sub>Bm</sub> would be like:</p>
<p>|----+----| <br>
| 1' | 2' | <br>
|----|----| <br>
| 3' | 4' | <br>
|----|----| <br></p>
<p>Then the buffer would be of great help for us.</p>
<p>Opperations are like:</p>
<ul>
<li>1 T-&gt; buffer 1</li>
<li>2 T-&gt; buffer 2</li>
<li>4 T-&gt; 4'</li>
<li>buffer 2 -&gt; 3'</li>
<li>3 T-&gt; buffer 2</li>
<li>buffer 1 -&gt; 1'</li>
<li>buffer 2 -&gt; 2'</li>
</ul>
<p>Here T stands for transpose and '-&gt;' stands for move, all operations are based on a 4*4 submatrix base.</p>
<p>These operations designed in 4 * 4 should only causes 16 misses for the transpose of a 8 * 8 submatrix. There would be some submatrixs left, but they are easy to handle.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
